BRYANT "CHASE" ORTEGA

Web Developer

github.com/bryant-ortega linkedin.com/in/Bryant-0rtega/

(909) 964-4444

chase@monarca.systems

Glendale, California

Education

Full-Stack Certificate CareerFoundry 2023

Loyola Law School Los Angeles, CA

University of California Riverside, CA B.A. History

Skills

HTML, CSS, JS

Responsive Design

Bootstrap library

Leadership and People Development

jQuery

Node.js

Git

TDD

Chrome Dev Tools

Postman

Quickbooks, Excel

Slack, Zoom, Discord

Interests

Solidity Development

Ethereum Blockchain

Languages

English, Spanish

Summary

Web developer with a background in E-commerce, logistics, and manufacturing; specializing in business software. Experienced in building customized web based tools, and apps for small businesses. Leverage analytical mindset, entrepreneurship, creativity, and excellent communication to build industry disrupting software.

Experience

Monarca Systems - Los Angeles, CA - Consultant - 04/2022 - present

- E-commerce, manufacturing, process improvement, and Software consulting.
- Automated documents process for law a firm saving them \$130K + annually.

The Hyv, LLC - Los Angeles, CA - Founder/CEO - 07/2013 - 06/2022

- Operated company from inception to 15 employees and \$9M annual gross.
- Directed finances and coordinated budgets, maximizing investments and increasing efficiency resulting in 100-150% average increase in annual gross.
- Designed and developed two proprietary web applications to automate and optimize processes.
- Developed and implemented administrative policies, increasing productivity and improving employee satisfaction and retention.
- Adapted systems to guickly scale warehouse output capacity by 1000%.

SWRM, LLC - Los Angeles, CA - Startup Founder — 08/2018 - 09/2021

- Invented a new method of print on demand apparel category: "Off Market"
- Developed an integrated barcode system to organize and scale production.
- Crafted and pitched deck to multiple investors to secure next round funding.
- Launched a working beta version of our online tool & marketplace.

STFUPOP, LLC - Los Angeles, CA - Founding Partner — 04/2015 - 09/2021

- Grew an independent contractor to a 6,000 sq. ft. LLC with10 employees.
- Facilitated 1000% increase in output by expanding equipment and services.
- Secured strategic partnership, increasing annual gross up to \$400K.

Web Development

Personal project, CareerFoundry, July – August 2023

- Developed a progressive web application with React to fetch events from a Google Calendar API.
- Used test-driven development (TDD) technique, translating user stories into scenarios for various testing with Jest, Cucumber, and Puppeteer.
- Implemented the 0Auth protocol and AWS Lambda's authorization function to gain access to the protected Google Calendar API.